commonsensehome.com 2019-04-24

# Privacy Policy

## Common Sense Home Privacy Policy

### SUMMARY

We do track some personal information. We use cookies to see if you have visited. Our advertisers track some of your activity and we use your email to send you offers from time to time. We make money from the advertising, and we also make some money if you buy stuff on sites we link to. You can opt out of the email (click unsubscribe at the bottom of ALL Common Sense Home emails). You can also use software to disable cookies or advertising.

### COOKIES

Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the sites or service providers systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information

We use cookies to understand and save your preferences for future visits, keep track of advertisements and compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may contract with third-party service providers to assist us in better understanding our site visitors. These service providers are not permitted to use the information collected on our behalf except to help us conduct and improve our business.

### CHILDREN

Anyone under 16 years of age MUST obtain parental consent before posting a comment, sharing personal information or subscribing to our email service.

## WHAT WE TRACK

Site visits, unique visits, pageviews, device, O/S or browser, page activity (ie which pages you view and in what order) we also track rough location using TCP/IP information through Google – but we don’t have direct TCP/IP tracking information – only aggregate data. Disabling cookies will disable much of this tracking. Common Sense Home LLC doesn’t track or store credit card information.

### OPTIONAL INFORMATION WE TRACK

You might also share information with us through optional, voluntary submissions, direct emails to us or other forms. You can chose NOT to fill these out, such as subscribing to our email newsgroups. You can also chose to participate in our forums (comments section) on each post.

You may also choose to share our site using share buttons, again, some information is tracked. These are all voluntary. Note we require a double opt-in for email; you must click and enter your email – and then agree via an email.

## HOW WE USE THE DATA

We use the tracked information for advertising, tracking who is reading what, and help us determine what we should work on and what we shouldn’t. Primarily cookies. This allows us to use Google Analytics to get statistics about site usage. We also have some WordPress specific tracking and plugin tracking, some of the security tools track the source of actual or suspected attacks.

### How exactly is your information used?

  * Emails
    * Newsletters Emails
    * Advertising/Affiliate Link Emails
  * In the comments section (in each page or post on the website)
  * Review of site content, flow, links and content analysis
  * To personalize your experience – your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs.
  * To improve our website – we continually strive to improve our website offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you.
  * To improve customer service – your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs
  * To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature

## HOW WE PROTECT YOU

We never sell your email. We never sell our lists, ever. If you unsubscribe (you can at the bottom of every email) we will stop sending all future emails. We do protect the commonsensehome.com using various tools to stop malware and hacking and spam. Common Sense Home encrypts all web traffic to and from commonsensehome.com using HTTPS.

## NEWSLETTER AND ADVERTISING EMAIL

If you voluntarily join our email newsgroup by entering your email in a subscription page or popup and then confirming with the email, we will send you emails. Our email provider is AWeber. The privacy policy for AWeber is here: [https://convertkit.com/privacy/](https://www.aweber.com/privacy.htm)

## COMMON SENSE HOME PARTNERS

These are considered 3rd party data processors or 3rd party agents of Common Sense Home LLC

 **AWeber**  – provides email newsletters and email advertising services. They use cookies for link tracking

 **AdThrive** – our advertising company – they display all the ads on the page at our direction – they use source IP address, O/S, browser and cookies

 **Google** – provides site analytics and search features for us to keep the site operational. They primarily use cookies and source IP address

 **Succuri** – is our security and content delivery network provider – they track some activity, specifically IP address and suspected or actual attack detail.

 **Gravatar**

 **e-Junkie** – is used to allow us to sell our CommonSenseHome Never Buy Bread Again paper and electronic books.

 **LiquidWeb** – is our website provider and support entity. They are located in the USA. This is a link to their privacy page: <https://www.liquidweb.com/about-us/policies/privacy-policy/>

Other Product Affiliates – we use numerous affiliates with product links. See each affiliate for their individual privacy statements.

### Amazon Affiliate Disclosure

Common Sense Home is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to Amazon.com. This does not alter the price for you in any way, but supports the Common Sense Home website.

### Third party links

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

## OUR PROMISE

We care about the information we share, and the information you share with us. We only share what we believe to be reliable proven information. Your information will only be used by us, and you have the option to block it by unsubscribing or blocking ads/cookies.

## WE NEVER REQUEST YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

If you ever get an email request for personal information from us DELETE IT. We never request personal information via email. If you see a webpage using our logo but the URL doesn’t match our website, don’t enter your information.

### Do we disclose any information to outside parties?

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

### Credit cards and other personal information

We don’t store your personal information such as credit cards, that is all done between you and a 3rd party. We sell our books through eJunkie and their privacy page is here: https://www.e-junkie.com/wiki/privacy

## LEGAL COMPLIANCE

We do our best to be compliant with all the rules. If you find anything not in compliance please let us know at [compliance@commonsensehome.com](mailto:compliance@commonsensehome.com).

We work to be in compliance with all US Federal and State laws. Including the

US CAN SPAM ACT – we use ConvertKit as our mass email provider.

We also try to be compliant with: UK Data Protection Act 1988 (DPA); EU Data Protection Directive 1995 (DPD); EU General Data Protection Regulation 2018 (GDPR); and Australian Privacy Act 1988 (APA).

### California Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance

Because we value your privacy we have taken the necessary precautions to be in compliance with the California Online Privacy Protection Act. We therefore will not distribute your personal information to outside parties without your consent.

### Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance

We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act), we do not collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age. Our website, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years old or older.

## OTHER FORUMS NOT ON OUR WEBSITE

We maintain user forums or group pages on Facebook, Google+ and on MeWe. These lists are entirely voluntary. Common Sense Home does not share membership or personal information that is shared on those forums. Note however, Facebook, Google+ or MeWe may use the information outside of our knowledge. See the privacy pages for those services for more information. Also we recommend be careful on links in public forums, as anyone can post links and those links may be dangerous.

## COMMENTS SECTION

Each post on CommonSenseHome has a comments section. Adding a comment is voluntary. We may chose to publish a comment, or delete it. We may delete comments along with a post if the post is no longer needed. If you want to change or delete a comment you can email us at comments@commonesnehome.com or you can post a comment requesting the deletion. We suggest you avoid adding personally identifiable information in any comment posted to a Common Sense Home webpage.

### How we store your comment data

The only real personal information we directly track are your comments. Those are stored in WordPress on the website. The information is identifiable, and is not encrypted. If you choose to post be aware that information is publicly available. The remainder of the data

## Terms and Conditions

Please also visit our Terms and Conditions section establishing the use, disclaimers, and limitations of liability governing the use of our website at <https://commonsensehome.com/terms-of-use/>

## DATA CONTROLLER

The data controller of this website is:

Common Sense Home LLC (a limited liability company)

### Mailing address is:

PO Box 144  
Denmark WI 54208

### Data Protection Officer

Mr August Neverman  
CIO, CimmonSenseHome LLC  
Telephone: US 262-207-4194  
Email: compliance@commonsensehome.com

## CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY

Our privacy policy may change over time. We won’t send you updates for very little change, but you can check here any time you want to see what has changed.

5/12/2018 – GPDR Specific Changes Published

3/28/2014 – Policy first published
